<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Benevides&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Benevides&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mtrsk.github.io/categories/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Have 10 Seconds To Nixify Your Dotnet Project</title>
      <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2024/you-have-10-seconds-to-nixify-your-dotnet-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2024/you-have-10-seconds-to-nixify-your-dotnet-project/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Don &amp;ldquo;The Gun&amp;rdquo; Syme, now officially part of the &amp;ldquo;Nix Gang&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;While this is a click bait title (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve also farmed some zoomer credits out the OC), I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that&amp;rsquo;s how Don Syme feels when looks at a Result type like Result&amp;lt;&#39;T,string&amp;gt; in an F# codebase. The reason why I&amp;rsquo;ve written this post is that I started doing changes in a open source project I develop/maintain, and realized other .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiments With Erlang And Nix</title>
      <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2024/experiments-with-erlang-and-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2024/experiments-with-erlang-and-nix/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been collaborating with friends on Lyceum, an MMO game with an Erlang backend and a Zig + Raylib client (as if erlang wasn&amp;rsquo;t a weird enough of a choice). Now, this is an unusual combination, but that&amp;rsquo;s the whole reason our pesky group exists in the first place (if you want to know more check my friend&amp;rsquo;s Lemos post).&#xA;There is also a couple of standards we try to follow when doing this project, all of the team works with microservices all day in their normal jobs, so whenever we want to do something we try follow some simple rules:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Use Private Neovim Plugins On Nixos</title>
      <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2023/how-to-use-private-neovim-plugins-on-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2023/how-to-use-private-neovim-plugins-on-nixos/</guid>
      <description>Over time my config changed a lot since the early days, as of now I&amp;rsquo;m using a combination of Flakes and home-manager to manage my workstations. I try not to overthink too much when it comes to Nix, my current Neovim setup is pretty simple, lua-based, yet, fully nixified.&#xA;dotfiles ├── (...) ├── nvim │ ├── files.lua │ ├── line.lua │ ├── lsp.lua │ ├── settings.lua │ ├── tabs.lua │ └── treesitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching To Nixos</title>
      <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2018/switching-to-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/2018/switching-to-nixos/</guid>
      <description>After quite some time being a Debian user I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to become a full time meme distro user. At first I was following some of the manuals in an attempt to recreate my config in virtualbox. A day later this distro seemed too cool not to try it out for real, so why not?&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s kinda weird to adapt, in Debian I was accostumed to just run a command here and there and have a bunch of config files across my system, with Nix (the configuration language) one can have a single file (configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mtrsk.github.io/blog/</guid>
      <description>Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find my latest content, projects, tutorials and ramblings.&#xA;dotnet fsi posts.fsx </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
